medpages.co.za 2018-01-27

# Medpages Privacy Policy

####  Medpages respects your privacy and takes steps to protect it. This Privacy Policy applies to all our data collection and management activities, including those directly related to this website. We strive to make this Site a safe environment for everyone who visits it and uses our services. 

##### By visiting this website, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy describes why we collect information, what information we collect, and what we do (and do not do) with it. It also explains how you can change it. 

This does not address the practices of any website we link to. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into, and subject to our Terms of Use.

## Why does Medpages collect information?

Information management and communication technologies play a fundamental role in the activities of Medpages. Our principal activity is a manager and provider of healthcare information. We collect and maintain a limited set of information about the healthcare industry, and provide this information to our customers, as well as making it available to the providers of information and the individual healthcare professionals about whom information is held. 

## How can I contact Medpages?

You can contact Medpages as follows:

Organisation Name: | Medpages  
---|---  
Postal Address: | P.O. Box 322, Green Point, 8051  
Country: | South Africa  
Controller: | Medpages (Pty Ltd)  
Contact: | 

Tel: [+27 21 441 9700](tel:+27214419700)

Fax: +27 21 441 9701  
  
Website: | [www.medpages.info](http://www.medpages.info/)  
  
## What should I know about privacy and the Medpages services and website?

#### Medpages services

Medpages collects information about healthcare service providers and other persons and organisations in the healthcare industry in Southern Africa. All of this data is verified with the individual or representative of the organisation concerned, and their permission requested to include it in our active database. All persons and organisations are given the specific option to not have their information made available through our publications, subscription services and other services. When an individual or organisation chooses not to have their information listed, then we retain a copy of the data so as to avoid future duplication or error. 

#### Anonymous access

You can access our website home page and browse our site without disclosing your personal data.

## Automatic collection of information

We link information that is automatically logged about specific individuals who are required to log on to the website to use certain features with personal data already provided by them. We do this for the purpose of: 

  * Customer administration
  * Technical administration of the website
  * Research and development
  * Marketing

We use cookies to store data for specific users in order to personalise the search.

Note: Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your web browser to enable our systems to recognise your browser and to provide features. 

## Data collection and purpose specification

We do collect the personal data that you may volunteer while using our services.

We may also collect information about you from other sources, such as public records or bodies, or private organisations.

To access the table of personal data collected and purposes for which they are used, please click here

Please specifically note that we collect and use personal data for the purpose of publishing in a healthcare professional service provider directory (online format), and the provision of other related services to the healthcare industry, including data subscription services. 

You are invited to review the personal information held about you, if any, and to modify or update this information. To do this:

  * If you have a login, log in and then click the Update My Record link (top right of page).
  * Technical administration of the website

## Children's privacy

We do not knowingly collect personal data from children. We do not take specific steps to protect the privacy of children who disclose their personal data to us. 

## Disclosure and visitor choice

We do disclose our visitors' personal data to our subsidiaries or other organisations.

Where we disclose your personal data for the same purposes as those indicated in the table below, we provide you with the means to opt-out of disclosure by: 

  * Sending an email to: [info@medpages.info](mailto:info@medpages.info)
  * Sending postal mail to: PO Box 322, Green Point, 8051, South Africa
  * Calling this telephone number: [+27 21 441 9700](tel:+27214419700)
  * Sending a fax to this number: +27 21 441 9701

## Confidentiality / security

We do not give visitors to our website the option of using a secure transmission method to send us their personal data. 

We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from:

  * Unauthorised access
  * Improper use or disclosure
  * Unauthorised modification
  * Unlawful destruction or accidental loss

All our employees and data processors who have access to, and are associated with, the processing of personal data, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our visitors' personal data. 

We ensure that your personal data - except that which is published or otherwise made available to the public and our clients during the normal course or our business - will not be disclosed to state institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation. 

## How can I see the personal data that may be held about me?

Please read our [Manual](http://medpages.info/mphtml/v2/pdf/Medpages_PAIA_Manual.pdf) in terms of Section 51 of the Promotion of Access to Information Act which details the process to follow to request your personal information. 

Upon request, we will provide you with a copy of the personal information and we welcome your examination of the information that we hold about you and, where appropriate, you may have the information: 

  * Rectified or amended
  * Completed
  * Flagged as not for publication

We reserve the right to refuse to provide you with a copy of your personal information. We do, however, allow you to challenge that decision should this occur for any reason. 

## What are my legal rights in relation to this privacy policy?

Our privacy policy is compliant with the South Africa Open Democracy Act.

It is also compliant with the following global self-regulatory instrument: UN Guidelines for the Regulation of Computerised Personal Data Files Adopted by General Assembly Resolution 45/95 of 14 December 1990. 

We cannot demonstrate that our privacy policy accords with the privacy instruments.

If you choose to visit medpages.info or to purchase and/or make use of a Medpages publication or service, then both your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Policy, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application according to the law of the Republic of South Africa. 

## Privacy support

If you have an enquiry or concern about our privacy policy, please contact:

Contact  
---  
Name : | Marda de Beer  
Designation : | Information Officer  
Address : | Cape Town  
Phone Number : | [+27 (0)21 441 9700](tel:+27214419700)  
Fax Number : | +27 (0)21 441 9701  
Email address : | [marda@medpages.info](mailto:marda@medpages.info)  
URL : | [www.medpages.info](http://www.medpages.info/)  
  | Contact  
---|---  
Name : | Marda de Beer  
Designation : | Information Officer  
Address : | Cape Town  
Phone Number : | [+27 (0)21 441 9700](tel:+27214419700)  
Fax Number : | +27 (0)21 441 9701  
Email address : | marda@medpages.info  
URL : | [www.medpages.info](http://www.medpages.info/)  
  
#### Acknowledgement

This Privacy Statement is based on that recommended by the Organisation for Economic Co-Operation and Development (OECD) using the OECD Privacy Policy Statement Generator available at [www.oecd.org](http://www.oecd.org/) , October 2001. 

## Information collected

#### Tables of data collected and purposes for which they are used

We collect primary personal data and business information from the following sources:

  * volunteered by individuals, including visitors
  * collected from public records or bodies
  * collected from private organisations.

The nature of the information collected, and the use to which it is put, is indicated where applicable with an a . Information which is not collected or used is indicated with a . 

Primary personal data  
---  
Name  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Gender  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Address  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Email address  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Phone/fax number  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Business information  
Employer / organisation  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Job title  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Address  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Email address  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Phone/fax number  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
  | Technical administration of website | Research & development | Customer administration | Marketing | Trading in personal data  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
Primary personal data  
Name |  |  |  |  |   
Gender |  |  |  |  |   
Address |  |  |  |  |   
Email address |  |  |  |  |   
Phone/fax number |  |  |  |  |   
Business information  
Employer / organisation |  |  |  |  |   
Job title |  |  |  |  |   
Address |  |  |  |  |   
Email address |  |  |  |  |   
Phone/fax number |  |  |  |  |   
  
We collect certain other personal details and profiling data from the following sources:

  * volunteered by individuals, including visitors
  * collected from public records or bodies
  * collected from private organisations

The nature of the information collected, and the use to which it is put, is indicated where applicable with a . Information which is not collected or used is indicated with a . 

Personal details  
---  
Physical description  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Family characteristics  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Education and skills  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Lifestyle or personal tastes  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Financial resources  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Identifiers  
On-line identifiers  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Financial identifiers  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Identifiers assigned by public bodies  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Biometrics identifiers  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Specific Data  
Racial or ethnic origin  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Political opinions  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Religious or philosophical beliefs  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Trade union membership  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Health/medical data  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Sexual orientation  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
Police/justice data such as civil/criminal actions brought by or against the visitor  
Technical administration of website |   
Research & development |   
Customer administration |   
Marketing |   
Trading in personal data |   
  | Technical administration of website | Research & development | Customer administration | Marketing | Trading in personal data  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
Personal details  
Physical description |  |  |  |  |   
Family characteristics |  |  |  |  |   
Education and skills |  |  |  |  |   
Lifestyle or personal tastes |  |  |  |  |   
Financial resources |  |  |  |  |   
Identifiers  
On-line identifiers |  |  |  |  |   
Financial identifiers |  |  |  |  |   
Identifiers assigned by public bodies |  |  |  |  |   
Biometrics identifiers |  |  |  |  |   
Specific Data  
Racial or ethnic origin |  |  |  |  |   
Political opinions |  |  |  |  |   
Religious or philosophical beliefs |  |  |  |  |   
Trade union membership |  |  |  |  |   
Health/medical data |  |  |  |  |   
Sexual orientation |  |  |  |  |   
Police/justice data such as civil/criminal actions brought by or against the visitor |  |  |  |  |
